David L. Adei

Doctoral Candidate • Department of Computer Science • North Carolina State University

Website: lokingdav.github.io Email: lokingdav@gmail.com Github: github.com/lokingdav Mobile: +1-984-895-2720

Professional Summary

My research focuses on secure systems and applied cryptography, particularly designing secure systems to combat telecom fraud and strengthen system security. Currently, I am developing techniques to secure telephone networks and expand the coverage of the STIR/SHAKEN caller authentication framework. I am pursuing PhD after 6 years of industry experience.

EDUCATION

1. PhD — North Carolina State University — Raleigh, NC State, USA.

August 2022 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science, advised by Dr. Bradley Reaves.

Relevant Coursework: Cryptography, Computer & Network Security, Operating Systems Security, Advance Network Security, Cellular and Telephone Network, LLMs In Security and Software Security

2. BSc — Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology — Kumasi, Ghana.

August 2015 - July 2019

BSc in Computer Science, First Class Honors

— Graduated as best computer science student.

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

1. Jäger: Automated Telephone Call Traceback

<u>David Adei</u>, Varun Madathil, Sathvik Prasad, Bradley Reaves, Alessandra Scafuro ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS) Oct. 2024

Research Papers Under Review — Preprints

1. How to Recover a Cryptographic Secret From the Cloud

David Adei, Chris Orsini, Alessandra Scafuro, Tanner Verber

Available on Cryptology ePrint Archive: https://eprint.iacr.org/2023/1308

Expertise & Skills

Languages: Python, C++, JavaScript, JAVA, PHP, HTML & CSS

 $\textbf{Frameworks:} \qquad \text{Node.js, React.js, Vue.js, Express.js, Laravel, Flask, Progressive Web Applications} (PWA)$

Tools: Docker, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, LATEX, Git, REST API

Platforms: Linux, Web, MacOS, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

Soft Skills: Mentoring, Efficient Time Management, Leadership, Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Attention to Detail,

Written & Oral Communication

EMPLOYMENT & EXPERIENCE

- 1. Graduate Research Assistant NC State University Raleigh, NC, USA. In-Person Aug. 2022 Present
 - Developed secure cryptographic protocols for privacy-preserving call traceback and a scalable system to process 50,000 call records per second while minimal system resources.
 - Implemented performant Witness Encryption Scheme based on BLS signatures in C++, achieving 200% increase in speed.
 - $\bullet \ \ \text{Implemented credential-less secret recovery protocol using Trusted Execution Environments} (\text{TEEs}) \ \text{and blockchain}.$
 - Implemented a security game with deceptive prompt-injecting attacks on Large Language Models (LLM) to solve cryptographic puzzles.
 - Researched Peer-to-Peer (P2P) networks and distributed systems to enhance performance and security.
 - Technologies: C++, Python, Docker, Bash Scripting, Blockchain, AWS Nitro Enclave, MongoDB, Clickhouse Columnar Database, Large Language Models.
- 2. Senior Developer Scopic Software Rutland, MA, USA. Remote, Contractual Oct. 2021 Aug. 2022
 - Implemented web applications for image manipulation, 3D modeling, and data synchronization between Teamwork.com and Jira Cloud with overall 35% increased in client satisfaction.
 - Refactored core modules to improve frontend speed by 56%, reducing page load times significantly.
 - Resolved critical production bugs, reducing server downtime by 48% and bug rates by 36%.
 - Containerized 4 projects with Docker, cutting deployment time by 90%.
 - Upgraded outdated SDKs an API backend to reduce system crashes and increased uptime by 80%.
 - Technologies: Python, PHP, Vue.js, React, Node.js, MySQL, Docker.
- 3. Senior Software Engineer Cmunily Raleigh, NC, USA. Remote, Contractual Nov. 2020 Oct. 2021
 - \bullet Replaced legacy web app with a cross-platform, offline-first mobile app, improving speed by 26% and user engagement by 48%.
 - Redesigned monolithic ad-matching platform into a microservices architecture, improving scalability by 40%.
 - Technologies: Python, PHP/Laravel, Vue.js, MongoDB, PWA, Apache Cordova, IndexedDB, Docker, JWT, Micro Services.

- 4. Software Engineer Clearcare Solutions Ltd Stafford, England. Remote, Contractual Nov. 2019 Oct. 2020
 - Migrated legacy PHP app for 1,000 DAUs to Laravel, improving performance by 630x and increasing DAUs by 23%.
 - Overhauled frontend, enhancing user interface and boosting UX satisfaction by 15%.
 - Technologies: PHP/Laravel, Vue.js, Python, MySQL, Docker, Vagrant.
- 5. Senior Software Engineer W3MSYS Company Limited Accra, GA, Ghana. Hybrid Jan. 2017 Nov. 2019
 - Led the development of a nationwide healthcare management system with 1,000 DAUs.
 - Designed a rate-limited Role-Based Access Control microservice handling 10,000 API requests/hour, achieving 99.99% uptime.
 - Managed a team of 3 developers through Agile resulting in 24% increase in team productivity.
 - Technologies: Python, PHP/Laravel, Vue.js, React.js, Node.js, Service Workers, MongoDB, MySQL, Docker.

6. Software Engineer — Freelancing.

Remote, Contractual — Sept. 2015 - Jan. 2017

- Collaborated with clients to design tailored software solutions, optimizing business operations.
- Delivered high-impact features across a variety of platforms and technologies.
- Technologies: Python, Java, Laravel, VueJS, ElectronJS MySQL, REST APIs, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

1. Witness Encryption Based on BLS Signatures

C++ library with Python bindings. Implements Witness Encryption Scheme (WES) based on BLS Signatures. https://github.com/wspr-ncsu/BLS-Witness-Encryption

2. Jäger: Automated Telephone Call Traceback

Python implementation of Jäger system components. Integrates Oblivious PRF protocol, Group Signatures, BLS signatures and WES.

https://github.com/wspr-ncsu/jaeger

3. How to Recover a Cryptographic Secret From the Cloud

Python implementation of a cloud-based secret recovery mechanism using blockchain and AWS Nitro Enclave in the presence of a malicious cloud provider.

https://github.com/wspr-ncsu/Secret-Recovery

Posters

1. PrivyTrace: Privacy-preserving trace back/forward of phone calls

<u>David Adei</u>, Bradley Reaves

Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), Feb 2023

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

1. External Reviewer – IEEE S&P

2. Web Development Team Lead – Google Developer Students Club Nov. 2018 - Sept. 2019

3. Research Assistant – Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology Apr. 2017 – May 2019

4. President of Computer Science, Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology Sept. 2017 - Sept. 2018